Guide to the William Thompson Dewart Collection of Frank A. Munsey and New York Sun Papers 1833-1944 MS 168
New-York Historical Society
- Series III: Publications
  - Subseries III.3: The Sun Rays, internal paper published by the Sun Club, social and cooperative organization of New York Sun employees
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. XVII-XVIII, 1942 February - December (Offsite-box 13, Folder 14)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. XIX, 1943 January - December (Offsite-box 13, Folder 15)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. XX, 1944 January - July (Offsite-box 13, Folder 16)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. XX, 1944 November (Offsite-box 13, Folder 17)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. I-II (bound), 1926 May - 1928 April (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. III-IV (bound), 1928 May - 1930 April (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. V-VI (bound), 1930 May - 1932 April (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
    - The Sun Rays, Vol. VII-VIII (bound), 1932 May - 1934 April (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
    - The Sun Rays, 1945, 1945 January - December (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
    - The Sun Rays, 1946, 1946 January - November (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
    - The Sun Rays, 1947, 1947 January - March (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
  - Subseries III.4: Books
    - The Story of the Sun by Frank M. Obrien, 1918 (Offsite-box 61, Volume 7)
- Series IV: Photographs, prints and drawings
  This series includes portraits of Frank Munsey and William Dewart; interior and exterior shots of the old Herald Tribune office at Herald Square; a carte-de-visite portrait of William Gordeon Bennett; a photograph and lithograph of Charles Lindbergh; and nine drawings (caricatures and cartoons) of or about Munsey.
  - Photographs of Frank Munsey, his father Andrew Munsey, and the family's homes, circa 1901, 1904, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of William T. Dewart and family, circa 1908, 1933-1937 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
  - Photographs of Frank Munsey, William Dewart, William Dewart Jr., and Thomas Dewart (from photograph morgue) (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2A)
  - Benjamin Day (reproduction lithograph) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
  - Photograph of Charles Lindbergh receiving award from Thomas W. Dewart; lithograph of Charles Lindbergh, 1927 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of typesetters at The New York Sun office, 81 Warren Street, 1887 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Carte-de-visite of William Gordon Bennett, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Photographs of the New York Herald Building, Herald Square (exteriors and interiors), circa 1920 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of the New York Herald building, Herald Square (exteriors and interiors), circa 1920 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of the New York Herald building, Herald Square (interiors, offices and reception area), circa 1920 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of the New York Herald building, Herald Square (interiors), circa 1920 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
  - Fulton Street 1849 (reproduction lithograph), showing Sun office, 1913 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of Tom Ross, winner of a New York Sun drawing competition, 1941 (Offsite-box 15, Folder 10)
  - Caricatures & cartoons (Oversize), circa 1915-1925 (Box OS-small)
    Nine caricatures and cartoons of or about Frank Munsey. Artists include Ellison Hoover (inscribed to Dewart), Jefferson Machamer (inscribed to Dewart), Jonathan Cassel (inscribed to Dewart), C. Kessler (inscribed to Dewart), C.R. Macauley (inscribed to Dewart), and others.
- Series V: Photograph morgue, New York Sun
  This series consists of an indexed file of film and glass plate negatives from the Sun's archives. The images are mainly portraits of authors, artists and business and political figures who were prominent in the 1930's and 1940's. In addition to "famous" figures of the time, there are images of more obscure figures such as judges, FBI agents, and corporate officers. Portraits of Sun staff are also included. There are also a few photographs of events and places.
  The series is organized into three subseries: Subseries V.1, Card catalog; Subseries V.2, Glass negatives; and Subseries V.3, Film negatives.
  The file card catalog in Subseries V.1 serves as an index to the negatives in Subseries V.2 and V.3. The catalog is arranged alphabetically. Portraits are arranged by the sitter's last name; other images are arranged mainly by location, such as "City of New York," or "India." Each card lists the number of the corresponding negative in the upper right hand corner. In some but not all cases, a photographic print is also attached.
  Negatives are individually sleeved and identified only by number. They are arranged sequentially, but film and glass negatives (which were originally interspersed) have been re-housed separately. This means that there are two possible locations for any specific negative number; accordingly, researchers looking for a particular negative should request the box with the appropriate range of negative numbers from both Subseries V.2, Glass negative, and V.3, Film negatives.
  Film negatives, which are nitrate film and are held in cold storage, must be requested at least 72 hours in advance and require a confirmed appointment to view.
  Negative numbers preceded by a letter are apparently not included in the card index. Identifying information for a few of these images is provided on the negative sleeve, but most are not identified. Among the subjects depicted are an early automobile race and a trip to Hawaii.
  - Subseries V.1: File card catalog
    - Index cards A-C, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 16)
    - Index cards C-F, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 17)
    - Index cards F-H, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 18)
    - Index cards H-M, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 19)
    - Index cards M-R, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 20)
    - Index cards R-W, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 21)
    - Index cards W-Z, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 22)
    - Unidentified prints, circa 1930's-1940's (Offsite-box 22)
  - Subseries V.2: Glass negatives
    - Glass negatives (10-5 to 11-39) (Box 23)
    - Glass negatives (11-40 to 11-130) (Box 24)
    - Glass negatives (11-138 to 12-49) (Box 25)
    - Glass negatives (12-50 to 12-159) (Box 26)
    - Glass negatives (12-166 to 13-54) (Box 27)
    - Glass negatives (13-55 to 14-7) (Box 28)
    - Glass negatives (14-8 to 15-51) (Box 29)
    - Glass negatives (15-52 to 16-27) (Box 30)
    - Glass negatives (16-28 to 17-15) (Box 31)
    - Glass negatives (17-16 to 17-72) (Box 32)
    - Glass negatives (17-74 to 19-31) (Box 33)
    - Glass negatives (20-5 to 12-28) (Box 34)
    - Glass negatives (21-29 to 22-23) (Box 35)
    - Glass negatives (22-29 to 22-83) (Box 36)
    - Glass negatives (22-84 to 23-42) (Box 37)
    - Glass negatives (24-1 to 26-1) (Box 38)
    - Glass negatives (26-2 to 28-4) (Box 39)
    - Glass negatives (28-5 to 28-84) (Box 40)
    - Glass negatives (28-85 to 29-22) (Box 41)
    - Glass negatives (29-23 to 32-4) (Box 42)
    - Glass negatives (32-5 to 32-89) (Box 43)
    - Glass negatives (32-91 to Z-250) (Box 44)
  - Subseries V.3: Film negatives
    These film negatives, which are nitrate film and are held in cold storage, must be requested at least 72 hours in advance and require a confirmed appointment to view.
    - Film negatives (10-1 to 11-181) (Box 45)
    - Film negatives (11-182 to 13-98) (Box 46)
    - Film negatives (13-100 to 15-76) (Box 47)
    - Film negatives (15-79 to 17-20) (Box 48)
    - Film negatives (17-29 to 21-9) (Box 49)
    - Film negatives (21-34 to 22-202) (Box 50)
    - Film negatives (23-3 to 28-185) (Box 51)
    - Film negatives (24-6 to 27-81) (Box 51A)
    - Film negatives (28-186 to 32-115) (Box 52)
    - Film negatives (32-116 to A-15-39) (Box 53)
    - Film negatives (A-15-40 to A-27-8) (Box 54)
    - Film negatives (A-28 to A-53-61) (Box 55)
    - Film negatives (A-54-1 to C-15-9) (Box 56)
    - Film negatives (C-17 to M-4-103) (Box 57)
    - Film negatives (M-4-11.1 to Z-159) (Box 58)
    - Film negatives (Z-161 to Z-236-9.14) (Box 59)
    - Film negatives (Z-236-9.15 to Z-293) (Box 60)
- Series VI: Scrapbooks
  This series includes three volumes of newspaper clippings relating to Frank Munsey's death, one volume of newspaper clippings regarding the subsequent purchase of the Sun by William Dewart, and one volume of newspaper clippings regarding the 100th anniversary edition of the Sun on September 2, 1933. Also included is a Tiffany presentation box containing a memorial to Munsey following his death.
  - Newspaper clippings commenting on Frank Munsey's death (1 of 3 volumes), 1925 December (Offsite-volume 8)
  - Newspaper clippings commenting on Frank Munsey's death (2 of 3 volumes), 1925 December (Offsite-volume 9)
  - Newspaper clippings commenting on Frank Munsey's death (1 of 3 volumes), 1925 December (Offsite-volume 10)
  - Newspaper clippings commenting on the purchase of the New York Sun by William T. Dewart, 1926 October (Offsite-volume 11)
  - Newspaper clippings commenting on the 100th Anniversary Number of the New York Sun, 1933 September 2 (Offsite-volume 12)
  - Tiffany-bound resolution mourning the death of Frank Munsey, 1925 December 29 (Offsite-volume 13)
- Series VII: Printing plates
  - Printing plates (copper) of the first issue of the New-York Commercial Advertiser (Plate 1 of 2), 1797 October 2 (Offsite-box oversize Plate 1)
  - Printing plates (copper) of the first issue of the New-York Commercial Advertiser (Plate 2 of 2), 1797 October 2 (Offsite-box oversize Plate 2)
  - Printing plates (metal) of the first issue of the New-York Commercial Advertiser, 1797 October 2 (Offsite-box 63, Oversize Plates 3-4)
  - Printing plate (metal), unidentified (Offsite-box 62, Oversize Plate 5)
  - Printing plate (replica) of the Armistice Day issue of the New York Sun, 1918 November 11 (Offsite-box 62, Oversize Plate 6)